dataviz.com 2012-06-10

# DataViz, Inc.

  |   |   |    
---|---|---|---  
| 

## Dataviz Privacy Statement

|   |    
  | At DataViz, we take your privacy very seriously. We are NOT in the business of selling, renting or disclosing your personally identifiable information to others. We have created this statement to describe our commitment to your privacy.  
  |  |   |    
  |   
We record IP addresses (the Internet address of a computer) to track sessions on our site. Tracking gives us an idea of which parts and pages of our site users are visiting, how often they visit them, and how long they spend there. We do not link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable. This means that even if your session is tracked, you still remain anonymous. 

We also track browser type and platform. We use this information to deliver customized information specific to a particular platform and to determine the "mix" of browser types accessing our site. This information helps us make our site operate correctly with your browser.

However, if you:

  * Purchase a product from DataViz
  * Register a new product
  * Download a trial version of our software
  * Sign up for a mailing list or enter a contest
  * Fill out a survey, or sign onto a page that requires authorization
  * Or enter into any other transaction with us,

You may be asked to provide us your name, e-mail address, phone number, fax number, postal address, credit card number (for purchases), and possibly other personal information. Additional demographic information may be optionally requested in order to improve our service to our customers. We may use the information you provide to:

  * Keep you informed of new releases of our products
  * Provide helpful hints and tips on how to use our products
  * Make special offers that we extend only to our registered customers.
  * Improve our site and the services we offer you.
  * In limited cases, we may share your registration information (name, address, etc.) with the manufacturer of a product you purchase from us -- but only when we inform you in advance of your purchase of the particular product.

In addition, some of our software products may include technology that, if an Internet connection is available, contacts DataViz servers with basic information about the user's installed copy of the product and the operating system and the types of programs it is used with. Prior to installing any software product, the end-user license agreement will tell you whether such technology is present and how it may be turned off.  
  
|  |  |   
  | 

Cookies are unique text files that are sent to your browser from a Web server. As you browse our web site, cookies are placed on your computer's hard drive including when you download, register and/or purchase software. Cookies may include registration numbers for any or all of your registered DataViz products. Because some cookies may contain registration number(s), they can be linked to personally identifiable information. DataViz does not provide any personally identifiable information from cookie data to third parties. DataViz may use a third party to analyze for DataViz general web site statistics such as number of pages viewed, browser types, etc. obtained from cookies. Cookies are used by DataViz for the following:

  * To track the method of your referral to our site
  * Anonymous statistical purposes
  * Shopping cart creation/modification (consequently, you will not be able to shop on our web site if your browser is not set to accept cookies)
  * To track your site session and present information, graphics or hyperlinks based on your session and/or write information to submission forms when contacting DataViz
  * To present information, offers and invitations (surveys, beta programs, etc.) based on your product registration and improve your experience with the site.

|   | 

We may collect, create and disclose to third parties aggregated, anonymous statistics regarding our sales, traffic analyses and other information regarding or collected through our web site. This information won't include individually identifiable data about you. 

We may also sometimes engage agents or contractors to perform services necessary to our operations (for example, delivery of products, distribution of e-mail, etc.). When we do, we may give them access to name, addresses or other information necessary for them to do their job for us, but not for any other purpose.

In limited cases, when you buy a third-party product from us, we will share your registration information (name, address, etc.) with the manufacturer of that product. That manufacturer then may use your data to contact you and might also share your data with others, depending upon that manufacturer's own privacy policy. We believe that the manufacturers whose products we sell typically will respect your privacy. But we don't control what they do with data they receive from us. We therefore recommend that you check the privacy policy of any third-party manufacturer whose products you choose to buy from us, including how to tell that manufacturer your e-mail opt-out preferences, request to update or delete your data, etc. If you have any questions about the data we give to third-party manufacturers of products you buy from us or which specific manufacturers we share information with, please contact us directly.

Finally, in the event our company or its assets were ever sold, our customer database naturally would be transferred to the new owner.

Except as described above, and except as may be required by law, we will not disclose your personally identifiable information to others without your consent.  
  
  |  |   
  | 

The information collected may be used for processing orders, personalizing the shopping experience, contests, promotions, newsletters, announcements, special offers, etc. 

When you download a trial version of one of our products, we reserve the right to send a reasonable number of e-mail follow-up messages with information regarding purchasing the software.

From time to time, we partner with companies whose products we believe will interest you. We don't normally give your information to our partners, but rather we inform you directly ourselves of these offers via e-mail or postal mail. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see the "Choose or Opt-Out" section below.

| 

**Trial or Demo Customers:** If you submit your e-mail address for a trial or demo version of DataViz software, you may receive one or more promotional e-mails from DataViz. Any promotional e-mail you receive will include options to unsubscribe. 

**Registered DataViz Customers:** Registered customers who do not wish to receive product announcements or special offers can update their information here or by contacting DataViz directly.  
  
  |  |   
  | 

If your personally identifiable information changes (such as your zip code), or if you no longer desire our service, we will endeavor to provide a way to correct, update or remove your personal data provided to us. This can be accomplished by contacting DataViz via e-mail, fax, phone or mail communication. Registered users can update their information here or by contacting DataViz directly.

| 

The DataViz site contains links to other Web sites. Although we do not provide any personally identifiable information to these companies, we cannot guarantee your privacy once you leave the DataViz site. We are not responsible for the privacy policies, practices or content of web sites with links on our site. We encourage you to read the posted privacy statement whenever interacting with any web site.  
  
  |  |   
  | 

Protecting your order information is important to us and we make every effort to protect your online order information by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology. However, some firewalls and certain versions of browsers don't permit communication through secure servers.

| 

If you have any questions or feedback regarding our privacy statement, please contact us as follows: 

DataViz, Inc.  
Merritt Corporate Woods  
612 Wheelers Farms Road  
Milford, CT 06461  
E-mail DataViz  
  
  |  |    
  |  |  You should check back for updates to this privacy policy since we may update it from time to time without notice. This page was last modified on March 2009.  
---
